In this video, we're going to talk about
trial balance reports in Dynamics SL and
then look at how you can print similar
reports in Business Central.
In SL, I've printed out the detailed
trial balance for a specific period of
time and included all accounts.
I can easily see balance information
that was posted to each account and
sub-account.
In addition to the detailed trial
balance, I've also printed out the aged
AR, allowing me to see aged information
for each of my customers and drill into
my customers that have balances that I
need to collect on.
Now let's look at Business Central and
how we can view and print similar trial
balance reports. To navigate to the
trial balance reports for general
ledger, we'll select the search icon and
enter in trial balance.
In the available options to select, you
can see how both the trial balance,
which is similar to the summary trial
balance in SL,
as well as the detailed trial balance.
In the detailed trial balance report
options window, I've indicated that I
would like a new page per GL account.
Also, in the filter area, you can filter
to a specific account or a range of
accounts, similar to how you would in
SL.
Now let's preview the report and see how
the information looks.
Here I can see the balance information
as well as the detailed transactions
posted to the account.
I can scroll through the report and see
each account is printed on a new page.
Now let's look at the summary trial
balance.
The summary trial balance report has
some different options to select from.
I have the ability to compare values
from last year or if I have configured
budgets in Business Central, I could
compare to the balance that would have
been budgeted. Below, I've selected to
include actual and comparison balances
and display the variance as a
percentage.
I'm also rounding to the nearest dollar.
Again, I can filter to a specific range
of accounts as well as enter a new date
range for the report.
You can see on the summary trial balance
how it compares this year's balance to
last year's as well as displaying the
variance as a percentage.
Next, let's look at the age reports for
customers.
In the search field, I will type aged
accounts.
In the list, you can see both the AP and
AR aging reports. If I select the aging
report option for AR, similar to SL, I
can select a date that I want to age the
report and if I want the age by
transaction date or due date. I can
select the report in detail.
I can also filter report to a specific
customer class.
Now, I can view the aging information
for each customer and focus on a
specific customer or customers with
balances overdue.
In addition to previewing the report in
the screen, I could also send the report
to PDF or Word.
Let's look at what it would look like if
it was in Excel.
I'll mark the print to Excel option and
preview the report again.
In Excel, I can easily perform
additional analysis or create different
visuals for the data.
And that's a look at trial balance
reports in Business Central.
To learn more about Business Central,
see the following resources.